Sarath Kumar. B

Phone: 9003703715 / 6383761630 Mail: mailtosarath1996@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://jocular-gnome-812344.netlify.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/sarath-babayaga

Profile Summary

Passionate front-end web developer with 2.6 years of experience using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for client-facing landing pages. Currently working as Associate HR Consultant for the past 2 years.

Work Experience

Company 2: CareerNet Technologies Pvt Ltd, Chennai

Designation: Associate HR Consultant

Duration: May 2021 – Till Date

Roles & Responsibilities

- To source potential candidates' profiles based on the requirements given by clients.
- To do a short interview to the candidate.
- To check with their availability for the interview scheduled date.
- To follow-up the candidate before and after the interview.
- To build a good rapport with the candidate and make sure that they attend the interview and join the organization.
- Maintain and update the data of the shortlisted candidates.
- Excellent sourcing potential in multiple platforms like Naukri Job posts, Naukri Resdex, LinkedIn and employee referrals.
- Familiar with both Boolean search and Semantic search.
- Screening calls, Mail confirmations to the shortlisted candidates.
- Co-ordinating with clients and getting feedbacks for the scheduled interviews and sharing the results to candidates.

Clients Handled: Cognizant, TCS, Mindtree, Virtusa, Tech Mahindra, EQ India, Deloitte

Skillsets worked

Primary: Full Stack Developer (Java, .Net, MERN, MEAN, LAMP), Python, MSCRM, Mainframe, Java Developer, .Net Developer, React Developer, Angular Developer, PHP Developer, UI/UX Designer, Web Developer, Front-End & Back-End Developer

Secondary: Salesforce, SAP (ABAP, FICO, Hana, PPQM, PIPO, MM, WM, SD, TM), Business Analyst, Test Engineer (Manual & Automation), Network Engineer, SQL Developer, ETL Developer (Ab Initio, Informatica, Power BI), Oracle DBA.

Company 1: Ignizee, Tanjore

Designation: Front-end Developer Duration: Oct 2018 – March 2021

Project 1:

Client: Equine Rescue Services (UK).

- worked on a CRM project for an UK based insurance company Equine rescue service.
- Worked in agile project task planning, scrums and status reporting
- worked on various programs like ReactJS, redux, TypeScript, Context API, NodeJS, MongoDB, web API, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, SQL server etc.
- Designing, development, Coding, documentation.
- Development of Nodejs API.
- Ensures major projects follow established timeline Communicates team needs to other departments
- Technologies used ReactJS, react native, context API, Redux, NodeJS, MongoDB.

Project 2:

Client: Test Coach

S.Chand Edutech presents TestCoach, India's first bilingual, web and app synchronized platform. SSC, Banking, and Railways Government Recruitment Exam Aspirants can practice with Topic-specific sectional test, Exam based Mock Test and become Exam ready. The most trusted App for 'Sarkari Naukri Exam preparation'. it is a One Stop Practice Solution for all SSC, Banking, Railways, Insurance, IIT, NEET, UPSC and other State Examination Aspirants. It also enables aspirants to stay updated with Exam Information, Notifications and Daily Current Affairs. All the Information, Questions, Practice Sets are available in two languages Hindi and English. It has 100k downloads with 1.78k reviews

Technologies: ReactJS, react native, Context API, redux, NodeJS, MongoDB.

web link: https://testcoach.in/dashboard

App link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.schandpublication.testcoach&hl=en_IN&gl=US

Deployed Project Links

- https://main--dashing-torrone-3780f7.netlify.app/
- https://main--starlit-smakager-4e5932.netlify.app/
- https://master--leafy-caramel-03f840.netlify.app/
- https://main--strong-toffee-165a79.netlify.app/

Certifications

• MERN Stack Developer certification from GUVI, IIT Chennai.

Academic Background

B.E (CSE): Jun 2014 – May 2018
P.R. Engineering College, Tanjore.

Marks Obtained: 6.31 CGPA.

XII Grade: May 2013 - April 2014

Maxwell Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Tanjore.

Marks Obtained: 60%

X Grade: June 2011 – April 2012 P.R. Public School, Tanjore.

Marks Obtained: 81%

Personal Details

Name: Sarath Kumar

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: 01 Sep 1996

Address: 2/3, Kurinji Street, Thangam Nagar, Municipal Colony, Thanjavur-613007

 Mobile:
 9003703715 / 6383761630

 Email ID:
 mailtosarath1996@gmail.com

Declaration

The above information provided are the best and true to my knowledge.

Sarath Kumar **Signature**